linkedin.com/in/jamesjonessoftware/ Durham, NC

james.russel.jones@gmail.com

Phone: 919.321.7043

### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## Design and Development of Enterprise Scale Applications with Large Data Requirements

Highly accomplished Full-Stack .NET and C# Software Developer with 12 years of experience in large scale application development for Enterprise Banking, Healthcare, and Manufacturing companies. Proven success with modernization and architecture redesign of mission-critical software applications meeting all production deadlines in a secure highly regulated environment. Signature accomplishments include the design and implementation of a web service at Charles Schwab using ASP.NET Core that provides portfolio and account management features for millions of accounts and trillions of dollars of financial assets. Developed software on a .NET-based front-office trading platform for Deutsche Bank which helped to manage a multi-billion-dollar portfolio of interest rate derivatives. Collaborates effectively with Executive Management, stakeholders, and the development team.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Software Development
- Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe)
- Large Scale Development
- Issue Tracking
- Legacy Platform Transitions
- Production Systems
- Project Leadership

- Software Design
- Web Services
- Test Driven Development
- Code Quality/Reuse
- High Volume Transactions
- Roadmaps
- Project Management

- Software Architecture
- Full Stack Developer
- Application Integration
- Predictive Analytics
- Lean-Agile Practices
- Business Requirements
- Mentor

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# CHARLES SCHWAB, DURHAM, NC STAFF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

7/2018- Present

### Integrate enhanced portfolio and accounting functions for the company's flagship offerings

- Design and implement a web service using ASP.NET Core that provides portfolio and account management features for millions of accounts and trillions of dollars of financial assets under custody at Schwab.
- Deliver significant value during each bi-weekly sprint deadline, demonstrating the ability to identify the critical path of getting features to production and then diligently facilitating that process from start to finish.
- Applies lean-agile practices at the enterprise level to identify critical paths, inter-team dependencies, ensure
  the product owner prioritizes the critical path and consistently hit future goals.
- Utilize test-driven development and dependency inversion/injection to maximize code quality.
- Facilitate Integration by running development environments side-by-side and debugging them interactively.
- Capitalize on 12 years of programming experience to advocate new approaches that increase the effectiveness of the team, particularly during retrospectives.

### **DEUTSCHE BANK, DURHAM, NC**

9/2015-7/2018

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

Developed software on a .NET-based front-office trading platform which helped manage a multi-billion-dollar portfolio of interest rate derivatives

- Implemented a variety of processes to support the calculation of XVA, such as BRDS integration, PKS equity integration, RMS integration, and reference data integration.
- Discovered a way to reliably remove concurrency locks from the trading system by implementing a temporal, immutable data model and asynchronous processing model, vastly improving throughput and system stability.
- Refactored, simplified and modernized a legacy codebase while increasing the scalability of the platform.

James Jones Resume, Page 2

Modernized trading software so that it runs an order of magnitude faster and remain in compliance with financial regulations, rendering the system easier to audit since the data was now immutable and could not be changed by other threads.

- Improved readability and resolved architectural issues during code reviews, providing actionable insights in an environment of strict regulatory control and price-sensitive information.
- Utilized Veracode static code analysis tools to identify and resolve security vulnerabilities.
- Implemented software to stream tens of millions of trades per day between web services.

#### PRECISION LENDER, DURHAM, NC

9/2014-7/2015

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPER** 

Full-stack .NET developer on a team responsible for developing a commercial loan pricing product hosted on Microsoft Azure

- Collaborated with the CEO and commercial loan bankers to develop new features on a commercial loan product that earns over \$4 million in revenue annually.
- Triaged and investigated bugs, including CPU-related performance issues.
- Re-platformed the flagship product from Silverlight to modern JavaScript/HTML5.

#### **HEALTH DECISIONS, DURHAM, NC**

8/2012-8/2014

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

Full-stack software developer of an ASP.NET-based bespoke clinical trial management system

- Appointed "Project Leader" for several successful development initiatives, building randomization, blinding, supply management, and security modules
- Collaboratively developed new components for the systems with the Business Analysis and Quality Assurance staff.
- Prepared, tested and deployed code to production on a bi-monthly release cycle while triaging and remediating any production issues that arose.

### LORD CORPORATION, DURHAM, NC

8/2006-8/2012

APPLICATION DEVELOPER (IS SPECIALIST)

FULL-STACK .NET SOFTWARE DEVELOPER FOR DOZENS OF LINE-OF-BUSINESS SOFTWARE SYSTEMS

- Modernized an elaborate system of interconnected services which coordinated major manufacturing activities, reverse-engineering Fortran line-by-line as the sole developer on this complex transformation.
- Collaborated with a Lord Corporation Fellow to create algorithms to model the behavior he was observing in the laboratory, resulting in developing a proprietary rubber elastomer blending simulator that could pull data from SAP and output instructions to fill orders.
- Top developer during tenure, saving millions of dollars in reduced rework and waste, decommissioned hardware, maintenance, and turnaround time, while increasing manufacturing productivity.
- Utilized predictive analytics to develop a Six Sigma quality control system and developed over a dozen SAP Business One add-ons and integrations.
- Mentored junior developers, familiarizing them with the security requirements of ITAR regulation.

**Technical Skills: Programming:** C#, ASP.NET, JavaScript, XAML, HTML5, FORTRAN **Framework**: Web API, MVC, MVVM, Entity Framework, NHibernate **Database**: MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server **Business:** SAP Business One API **Issue Tracking**: Atlassian Stack (Jira, BitBucket, Bamboo) **Code Analysis Tools**: Veracode, SonarQube, **Cloud:** Azure

#### Education

B.S. in Software Engineering, Minor in Management Information Systems, The Penn State University, PA